[Music]
emerging evidence suggests that higher
daily intake of fiber-rich fruits and
vegetables is associated with lower
incidences of anxiety and adults and at
the same time greater happiness higher
life satisfaction and greater emotional
well-being so persuading people to
consume more fruits and vegetables may
not only benefit their physical health
in the long run but also their mental
well-being in the short run
fruit consumption for example has
protective associations with leading
killers like heart disease stroke
diabetes and cancer as well as
depression the question is
why
several different mechanisms have been
proposed for example it may be the
antioxidants and
anti-inflammatory properties of produce
scavenging the free radicals that are
involved in some of the inflammation
associated with depression if that's the
case what about just taking vitamin c
supplements
the brain has some of the highest levels
of vitamin c in the body so the thought
is if we take extra vitamin c it may
have some sort of therapeutic role in
brain diseases especially given it's not
just an antioxidant but also has other
critical functions in the brain such as
helping to build neurotransmitters like
dopamine but you don't know whether it
actually helps until you
put it to the test
one study found a beneficial effect
adding vitamin c as an adjunct treatment
to an antidepressant while another study
found no benefit from vitamin c
supplementation so there are mixed
results for vitamin c and depression
here's another study that found no
benefit when it came to depression but
those randomized to vitamin c instead of
placebo pills did show a significant
decrease in anxiety level and this
wasn't only seen in this study the
effects of oral vitamin c
supplementation on anxiety in students a
double-blind randomized
placebo-controlled trial high school
students were given 500 milligrams a day
or placebo 500 milligrams of vitamin c
is about what you find in five oranges
four yellow kiwifruit or guavas or one
half yellow bell peppers
within just two weeks the vitamin c
reduced anxiety compared to placebo
along with providing a significant drop
in heart rate
given these data showing vitamin c may
have anxiety reducing effects
researchers sought to find out if only a
single dose could acutely affect
emotional states and indeed
within only two hours of taking some c
subjects experienced a significant drop
in anxiety compared to placebo though
only among those who started out the
most anxious in the first place
as a bonus vitamin c supplementation may
lower your blood pressure a few points
but whole fruits and vegetables can do
the same thing and may even do it better
for those who need it the most as i've
shown previously even just adding two
servings of fruits and vegetables a day
can have psychological well-being
benefits within only two weeks and you
won't be put at risk of kidney stones
like you would with vitamin c
supplements though that appears to be
only a problem in men
[Music]
you